Guide to the Alma Lutz Papers, 1906-1973
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Alma Lutz Papers
1906-1973
Lutz, Alma
33.4 cubic feet (62 boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Correspondence, clippings, notes, speeches, interviews, photographs, manuscript and published versions of her writings, other publications, bibliographies, and copies of historic documents pertaining to materials on women's history. There are also family letters and photographs, biographical materials, and miscellaneous items relating to Vassar College.
Biographical Note
Alma Lutz (1890-1973) was born in Jamestown, ND, and came to Vassar from the Emma Willard School. A leader in the fight for woman suffrage and equal rights, she was also author of several biographies of leading feminists. During her college years she was an active feminist; and after graduating from Vassar in 1912, she returned to North Dakota to work for women's suffrage. Six years later Alma Lutz moved to Boston, where she wrote for the National Woman's Party and did research on the role of women in American history. From that time her life was devoted to both activism and historical studies. In 1938 she served as editor of the official organ of the National Woman's Party, and was for many years a member of the party's national council.
Writer, as well as political activist, she wrote biographies of Susan B. Anthony, Elizabeth Cady Stanton, and Emma Willard; and collaborated with Harriot Stanton Blatch on Mrs. Blatch's memoirs, Challenging Years. She also wrote Crusade for Freedom, a history of women in the antislavery movement. Alma Lutz served on the advisory committee of the Schlesinger Library, was a consultant to Notable American Women, and secretary of the Massachusetts Committee for the Equal Rights Amendment.
Scope and Content Note
Correspondence, clippings, notes, speeches, interviews, photographs, manuscript and published versions of her writings, other publications, bibliographies, and copies of historic documents pertaining to materials on women's history at Radcliffe, Smith, and Vassar Colleges; women's history courses; the Lucy Stone League; the Margaret Brent Fellowship; the U.S. President's Commission on the Status of Women; the National Woman's Party; the equal rights amendment; Woman's Rights Conventions in Seneca Falls (1848) and Boston (1850 and 1859); woman suffrage; anti-slavery; Hannah Adams, Susan B. Anthony, Elizabeth Cady Stanton, Harriet Stanton Blatch, Abby Kelley Foster, Emma Hart Willard, and other prominent women in history; working women; women in World War II and the armed forces; women in other countries; and the Women's Liberation Movement. Major correspondents include Angelica Balabanoff, Pearl S. Buck, and Miriam Holden. There are also family letters and photographs, biographical materials, and miscellaneous items relating to Vassar College.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Related Materials
Alma Lutz Collection of English and American Women Authors
Alma Lutz Papers, Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College, Northampton, MA
Alma Lutz Papers, 1927-1946. Schlesinger Library, Radcliffe Institute, Harvard University, Cambridge, MA
Separated Materials
Some significant correspondence from the Lutz Collection was removed and placed in the Archives and Special Collections Library's Autograph Files.
Correspondents include: Florence E. Allen, Angelica Balabanoff*, Mary R. Beard, Alice Stone Blackwell, Vera Brittain, Pearl S. Buck, Henrietta Buckmaster, Lester B. Cutler, Bette Davis, Helen Gahagan Douglas, Betty Friedan, J. W. Fulbright, Barry Goldwater, Marjorie Barstow Greenbie, Miriam Holden, Fanny Hurst, Cordell Hull, Inez Haynes Irwin, Caroline Katzenstein, John F. Kennedy, Marya Mannes, Jeannette Marks, Burnita Shelton Matthews, Lakshmi N. Menon, Pauli Murray, Caroline O'Day, Mrs. E. Pethick-Lawrence, Ann M. Rosenberg, Katherine St. George, Margaret Sanger, Margaret Chase Smith, Parla Ulisla, Mable Vernon, and Mary E. Woolley.
*The Balabanoff letters were subsequently transferred to the Angelica Balabanoff Papers in 2009.
Subject Headings
Names:
Adams, Hannah, 1755-1831; Anthony, Susan B. (Susan Brownell), 1820-1906; Blatch, Harriot Stanton, 1856-1940; Foster, Abigail Kelley, 1810-1887; Stanton, Elizabeth Cady, 1815-1902; Willard, Emma, 1787-1870; Balabanoff, Angelica, 1878-1965; Buck, Pearl S. (Pearl Sydenstricker), 1892-1973; Holden, Miriam Young
Organizations:
Vassar College; Radcliffe College; Smith College; Lucy Stone League; Margaret Brent Fellowship; United States. President's Commission on the Status of Women; National Woman's Party; Woman's Rights Convention
Subjects:
Women's colleges--New York (State)--Poughkeepsie; Women's colleges--Massachusetts--Cambridge; Women's colleges--Massachusetts--Northampton; Women--Suffrage; Women--History--Study and teaching; Women's rights; Women in politics; Feminism; Slavery--Anti-slavery movements; Women--Employment; World War, 1939-1945--War work; War--Women's work; Equal rights amendments; Women--Social conditions; United States--Armed Forces--Women; Feminists; Women historians
Document Types:
Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence; Photographs; Printed ephemera
VCL Categories:
History and Historians; War and War Crimes; Women's History
Encoding Information
Encoded by Elizabeth Clarke, February 2007. Updated by Emma Gronbeck, March 2024.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the estate of Alma Lutz.
Arrangement
This collection is currently only partially processed. There is some description at the folder level, but most of the collection is described more generally at the box level. Two broad series have been identified ("Manuscripts of Speeches and Articles" and "Historical Biography Material"), but the rest of the collection is currently labeled "Miscellaneous."
Series List
- Series I. Manuscripts of Speeches and Articles, (Boxes 6-11)
- Series II. Historical Biography Material, (Boxes 12-20)
- Series III. Miscellaneous, (Boxes 1-5, 21-62)
Container List
- Series I. Manuscripts of Speeches and Articles
  - "Women's Role in American History, 1800-1860." (Boxes 6-11)
  - Speeches and articles on the 1848 Seneca Falls convention (Boxes 6-11)
  - "Women Were There: The Unsung Warriors of 1861." (Boxes 6-11)
  - ERA articles (Boxes 6-11)
  - "The Learned Lady: The Story of Hannah Adams (1755-1831)." 1935. Unpublished (Boxes 6-11)
  - Challenging Years: The Memoirs of Harriot Stanton Blatch (New York: Putnam, 1940) (Boxes 6-11)
  - Created Equal: A Biography of Elizabeth Cady Stanton (New York: John Day, 1945). 3 versions (Boxes 6-11)
  - With Love, Jane (New York: John Day, 1945). 2 versions. Also letters used in compiling the book; reviews and correspondence about the book (Boxes 6-11)
  - Susan B. Anthony (Boston: Beacon Press, 1959). First draft and carbon copy. Also a folder of correspondence with publishers. (Boxes 6-11)
  - Emma Willard: Pioneers Educator of American Women (Boston: Beacon Press, 1968). 2 carbon copies and a galley (Boxes 6-11)
  - Crusade For Freedom: Women of the Antislavery Movement (Boston: Beacon Press, 1968). Final copy marked for printer and 2 carbon copies. (Boxes 6-11)
  - Articles published by Lutz and leaflets supporting ERA, written by her (Boxes 6-11)
- Series II. Historical Biography Material
  - Adams, Abigail, (Copies from the Alma Lutz Collection) (Box 12)
  - Adams, Hannah, (Copies from the Alma Lutz Collection) (Box 12)
  - Adams, Hannah — Revision (Box 12)
  - Adams, Hannah — Letters (Box 12)
  - Adams, Hannah — Sources (Box 12)
  - Adams, Hannah — Correspondence re: Material (Box 12)
  - Adams, Hannah — Sources (Box 12)
  - Adams, Hannah (Box 12)
  - Adams, Hannah — Radcliffe Paper — Extra for Women's Archives in file, also duplicate (Box 12)
  - Adams, Hannah — Article (Box 12)
  - Adams, Hannah — First Carbon (Box 12)
  - Adams, Hannah — Preface and Bibliography (Box 12)
  - Adams, Hannah — Introduction (Box 12)
  - Adams, Hannah — Notes (Box 12)
  - Adams, Hannah — Early — History (Box 12)
  - Adams, Hannah — Mother and Father (Box 12)
  - Adams, Hannah — Childhood (Box 12)
  - Adams, Hannah — Youth (Box 12)
  - Adams, Hannah — Contemporaries — American Literature, etc. (Box 12)
  - Adams, Hannah — Copyright (Box 12)
  - Adams, Hannah — Middle Years (Box 12)
  - Adams, Hannah — View of Religions (Box 12)
  - Adams, Hannah — History of the Jews (Box 12)
  - Adams, Hannah — Comments on her Work (Box 12)
  - Adams, Hannah — Letters on the Gospels (Box 12)
  - Adams, Hannah — Character (Box 12)
  - Adams, Hannah — Last Years (Box 12)
  - Adams, Hannah — Friends (Box 12)
  - Adams, Hannah — Autobiography (Box 12)
  - Adams, Hannah — Feminism (Box 12)
  - Adams, Hannah — Outlines (Box 12)
  - Addams, Jane (Box 12)
  - Alcott, Louisa — Letters (Box 12)
  - Anthony, Susan B., (Copies from the Alma Lutz Collection) (Box 12)
  - Anthony, Susan B. — Diaries (Box 12)
  - Anthony, Susan B. — Diaries, (Copies) (Box 12)
  - Anthony, Susan B. — Diaries, (Copies) (Box 12)
  - Anthony, Susan B. — Speeches (Box 12)
  - Anthony, Susan B. — Ohioana Library Association, 1884-1901 (Box 12)
  - Anthony, Susan B. — Letters, mostly to Jessie Anthony, (Copies from the Los Angeles Public Library) (Box 12)
  - Anthony, Susan B., (Copies from the Lucy E. Anthony Collection) (Box 12)
  - Anthony, Susan B. — to Anna Howard Shaw, (Copies from the Lucy E. Anthony Collection) (Box 12)
  - Anthony, Susan B., (Copies, not from the Alma Lutz Collection) (Box 12)
  - Anthony, Susan B. — Speeches and Articles, (Copies) (Box 12)
  - Anthony, Lucy E. (Box 12)
  - Anthony, Susan B., (Copies from the S.B.A Memorial Collection, 17 Madison St., Rochester, NY) (Box 12)
  - Dann, Anna E., (Copies from the S.B.A Memorial Collection, 17 Madison St., Rochester, NY) (Box 12)
  - Anthony, Susan B. — to Amelia Bloomer — Seneca Falls Historical Society (Box 12)
  - Anthony, Susan B. — Copies, (Copies from the Garrison Papers, Smith College) (Box 12)
  - Anthony, Susan B. — to Anna E. Dann, (Copies from the S.B.A Memorial Collection, 17 Madison St., Rochester, NY) (Box 12)
  - Anthony, Susan B. — Copies of Letters about S.B.A. Signature, Envelope, etc. (Box 12)
  - Anthony Family — Letters, (Originals) (Box 12)
  - Anthony, Susan B. — Letters re: preservation of birthplace (Box 12)
  - Anthony Homestead (Box 12)
  - Anthony, Susan B. — Memorial, 1964 (Box 12)
  - Anthony Family (Box 12)
  - Anthony, Susan B. — Clippings (Box 12)
  - Bibliography (Box 12)
  - Anthony, Susan B. — to Harriet Taylor Upton, (Copies from the Women's College Library, University of Rochester) (Box 12)
  - Anthony, Mary S. — Letters, (Copies from the S.B.A Memorial Collection, 17 Madison St., Rochester, NY) (Box 12)
  - Anthony, Susan B. — to Clara Colby, (Copies from the S.B.A. Memorial Library, Los Angeles) (Box 12)
  - Anthony, Susan B. — to Lydia Coonley, (Copies from the S.B.A Memorial Collection, 17 Madison St., Rochester, NY) (Box 12)
  - Anthony Family (Box 12)
  - Anthony, Susan B. — Girlhood Rochester and Canajoharie (1845-1849) (Box 12)
  - Anthony, Susan B. — Civil War (Box 13)
  - Anthony, Susan B. — 1865-1866 (Box 13)
  - Anthony, Susan B. — 1840-1860 (Box 13)
  - Anthony, Susan B. — Kansas, 1867 (Box 13)
  - Anthony, Susan B. — 1868-1870 — The Revolution (Box 13)
  - Anthony, Susan B. — Suffrage Split, 1870 (Box 13)
  - Anthony, Susan B. — 1870-1872 (Box 13)
  - Anthony, Susan B. — Woodhull,1871 (Box 13)
  - Anthony, Susan B. — Trial (1872-1873) and Minor vs. Happersett (1875) (Box 13)
  - Anthony, Susan B. — Beecher — Tilton (Box 13)
  - Anthony, Susan B. — 1873-1880 (Box 13)
  - Anthony, Susan B. — 1880-1890 (Box 13)
  - Anthony, Susan B. — 1890-1893 (Box 13)
  - Anthony, Susan B. — 1894-1896 (Box 13)
  - Anthony, Susan B. — 1897-1899 (Box 13)
  - Anthony, Susan B. — 1900 (Box 13)
  - Anthony, Susan B. — Later Years (Box 13)
  - Anthony, Susan B. — Rochester, NY (Box 14)
  - Anthony, Susan B. — Miscellaneous Clippings (1906- ) (Box 14)
  - Anthony, Susan B. — Chronology, etc. (Box 14)
  - Anthony, Susan B. — Clippings (Miscellaneous to 1906) (Box 14)
  - Anthony, Susan B. — Comments (Box 14)
  - Anthony, Susan B. — and Elizabeth Cady Stanton — Contrasts (Box 14)
  - Anthony, Katharine — Biography (Box 14)
  - Anthony, Susan B. — Quotations (Box 14)
  - Anthony, Susan B. — Letters (Box 14)
  - Anthony, Biography — Reviews (Boston) (Box 14)
  - Anthony Biography — Reviews and Advance Copies (Box 14)
  - Anthony Biography — Beacon Press material (Box 14)
  - Anthony Biography — Publication (Box 14)
  - Anthony Biography — Index — S.B.A. (Box 14)
  - Anthony, Susan B. — Photographs, (Copies and originals) (Box 14)
  - Anthony Biography — Photographs (Box 14)
  - Anthony Biography — Corrections (Box 14)
  - Anthony Biography — Permissions (Box 14)
  - Anthony, Lucy E. — Interviews (Box 14)
  - Anthony, Biography — Notes — Revised Extra (Box 14)
  - Anthony Biography — Preface and Suggestions (Box 14)
  - Anthony Biography — Notes and Carbons (Box 14)
  - Anthony Biography — Letters re: Material (Box 14)
  - Anthony Biography — Extra Sheets — Preface etc. (Box 14)
  - Winter, Una R. — Letters (Box 14)
  - Powell, Rose Arnold — Letters, Statements, clippings (Box 14)
  - Anthony, Susan B. — S.B.A. Memorial, 17 Madison St., Rochester, NY (Box 14)
  - Anthony, Susan B. — S.B.A. Memorial Library, Los Angeles Public Library — Una R. Winter, Director (Box 14)
  - Howard, Martha [Mrs. George Howard] 1947-1954 — S.B.A. Memorial, Rochester, NY (Box 14)
  - Howard, Martha [Mrs. George] Letters 1955- (Box 14)
  - Anthony, Susan B. — Whereabouts of Scrapbooks and Books — Library of Congress — Diaries (Box 14)
  - Bacon, Ann Anthony — Letters (Box 14)
  - Anthony, Susan B. — Leaflets (Box 14)
  - Bacon, Ann Anthony — re: Right to Quote (Box 14)
  - Leaflets — Manuscript Notations (Box 14)
  - Anthony, Susan B. — Birthday Celebrations (Box 14)
  - Anthony, Charles (Box 15)
  - Anthony, Lucy — to Alma Lutz (Box 15)
  - Anthony, Susan B. — Articles (Box 15)
  - Anthony, Susan B. (Box 15)
  - Anthony, Susan — Children's Story (Box 15)
  - American Music Broadcast (Box 15)
  - Anthony, Susan B. (Box 15)
  - Anthony, Susan B. — Negatives of S.B.A., Colleagues, and George Francis Train (Box 15)
  - Anthony, Susan B. — Photographs for Book (Box 15)
  - Avery, Rachel Foster — Photograph (Box 15)
  - Letters — Miscellaneous (Box 15)
  - Women's Political Union (Box 15)
  - Balch, Emily Greene (Box 15)
  - Barton, Clara (Box 15)
  - Barton, Clara — Signed Photographs (Box 15)
  - Beard, Mary R. and Charles (Box 15)
  - Beecher, Catharine E. — Letter, (Copies from Alma Lutz Collection) (Box 15)
  - Beecher, Henry Ward (Box 15)
  - Belmont, Alva (Box 15)
  - Blackwell, Alice Stone (Box 15)
  - Blackwell, Alice Stone — Miscellaneous (Box 15)
  - Blackwell, Antoinette Brown, (Copies from Alma Lutz Collection) (Box 15)
  - Blackwell, Dr. Elizabeth, (Copies from Alma Lutz Collection) (Box 15)
  - Blackwell, Dr. Elizabeth (Box 15)
  - Blackwell Family (Box 15)
  - Blake, Lillie Devereux, (Copies from Alma Lutz Collection) (Box 15)
  - Blatch, Harriot Stanton, (Originals) (Box 15)
  - Blatch, Harriot Stanton — Photographs (Box 15)
  - Blatch, Harriot Stanton — re: Memoirs (Box 15)
  - Blatch, Harriot Stanton — 1856-1940 (Box 15)
  - Blatch Memoirs, Vassar 75th Anniversary Committee (Box 15)
  - Blatch, Harriot Stanton — Miscellaneous, (Copies) (Box 15)
  - Blatch, Harriot Stanton — Letters — From Mary Beard, (Copies) (Box 15)
  - Blatch, Harriot Stanton — Publication (Box 15)
  - Blatch Memoirs — Letters and Reviews (Box 15)
  - Blatch, Harriot Stanton — Publication (Box 15)
  - Blatch Memoirs — Letters and Reviews (Box 15)
  - Blatch, Harriot Stanton — Miscellaneous (Box 15)
  - Blatch Notes (Box 15)
  - Blatch Notes (Box 15)
  - Blatch, Harriot Stanton — Letters — National Woman's Party, (Copies) (Box 15)
  - Blatch Memoirs (Box 15)
  - Blatch, Harriot Stanton — re: Created Equal (Box 15)
  - Blatch, Harriot Stanton — Speeches, (Copies) (Box 15)
  - Blatch Memoirs — Letters prior to publication (Box 15)
  - Bloomer, Amelia (Box 15)
  - Bloomer Costumes (Box 15)
  - Booth, Mary L. (Box 15)
  - Boyer, Ida Porter — Woman Suffrage Letters (Box 15)
  - Breckinridge, Sophonisba Preston (Box 15)
  - Bremer, Frederika (Box 15)
  - Bright, Jacob (Box 15)
  - Brown, Brockden (Box 15)
  - Buck, Pearl S. (Box 15)
  - Bullard, Laura Curtis (Box 15)
  - Butler, Eleanor (Box 15)
  - Butler, Josephine E. (Box 15)
  - Carey, Phoebe and Alice, (Copies from Alma Lutz Collection) (Box 15)
  - Carroll, Anna Ella, (Copies) (Box 15)
  - Carroll, Anna Ella (Box 15)
  - Carteret, Elizabeth (Box 15)
  - Catt, Carrie Chapman, (Copies from Alma Lutz Collection) (Box 15)
  - Catt, Carrie Chapman, (Copies) (Box 15)
  - Catt, Carrie Chapman (Box 15)
  - Chandler, Thomas (Box 15)
  - Chandler, Thomas — Lundy (Box 16)
  - Chapman, Maria W., (Copies from Alma Lutz Collection) (Box 16)
  - Chapman, Maria W. — Biographical and Family — Anti-slavery to 1834 (Box 16)
  - Chapman, Maria W. — 1835-1836 (Box 16)
  - Chapman, Maria W. — 1835-1836 (Box 16)
  - Chapman, Maria W. — 1837-1840 (Box 16)
  - Chapman, Maria W. — 1840-1850 (Box 16)
  - Chapman, Maria W. — 1850-1869 (Box 16)
  - Chapman, Maria W. — Civil War, etc (Box 16)
  - Chapman, Maria W. — Foster (Box 16)
  - Chapman, Maria W. — 1870-1885 (Box 16)
  - Chapman, Maria W. — Standard (Box 16)
  - Chapman, Maria W. — Standard (Box 16)
  - Chiang Kai-shek, Madame (Box 16)
  - Child, Lydia Maria, (Copies from Alma Lutz Collection and Radcliffe Women's Archives) (Box 16)
  - Child, Lydia Maria, (Copies from Alma Lutz Collection) (Box 16)
  - Child, Lydia Maria (Box 16)
  - Colby, Clara Beurck (Box 16)
  - Cobden — Sanderson (Box 16)
  - Coonley, Queene Ferry (Box 16)
  - Corbin, Hannah Lee — Richard Henry Lee (Box 16)
  - Crandall, Prudence and P.C. Philleo (Box 16)
  - Crandall, Prudence — Letters — Cornell University and Connecticut College (Box 16)
  - Crandall, Prudence (Box 16)
  - Cunningham, Jane (Box 16)
  - Curtis, George William (Box 16)
  - Custer, Elizabeth B. (Box 16)
  - Dall, Caroline H. (Box 16)
  - Darling, Grace (Box 16)
  - Davis, Paulina W. — Correspondence re: Decade Meeting (Box 16)
  - Davis, Paulina Wright — Miscellaneous Letters (Box 16)
  - Davis, Paulina Wright (Box 16)
  - Dewey, Annie Godfrey (Box 16)
  - Dickinson, Anna E., (Copies from the Alma Lutz Collection) (Box 16)
  - Dickinson, Anna E. (Box 16)
  - Douglass, Frederick (Box 16)
  - Earhart, Amelia (Box 16)
  - Eaton, Harriet Cady (Box 16)
  - Eddy, Mary Baker (Box 16)
  - Eddy, Mry Baker — Amesbury (Box 16)
  - Eddy, Mary Baker — North Groton (Box 16)
  - Eddy, Mary Baker — Swampscott (Box 16)
  - Eddy, Mary Baker — Data — RUMNEY YEARS (Box 16)
  - Eddy, Mary Baker — THE RUMNEY YEARS for Longyear Foundation (Box 16)
  - Eddy, Mary Baker — RUMNEY YEARS — Letters (Box 16)
  - Eddy, Mary Baker — Quimby Period (Box 16)
  - Eddy, Mary Baker — CHRISTIAN SCIENCE SENTINEL articles (Box 16)
  - Eliot, George (Box 16)
  - Ellet, Elizabeth F., (Originals and copies) (Box 16)
  - Ellet, Elizabeth F., 1818-1877 (Box 16)
  - Englishwomen — Including correspondence with Scotland, Ireland, (Copies) (Box 16)
  - Englishwomen, (Copies from the Alma Lutz Collection) (Box 16)
  - Farnham, Eliza, (Copies from the Alma Lutz Collection) (Box 16)
  - Fern, Fannie (Box 16)
  - Flower, Benjamin O. (Box 16)
  - Follen, Eliza (Box 16)
  - Foster, Abby Kelley (Box 16)
  - Foster, Abby Kelley — Worcester (Box 16)
  - Miscellaneous, 1859-1870 (Mott — Foster) (Box 16)
  - Foster, Abby Kelley, 1859- (Box 16)
  - Foster, Abby Kelley, 1836-1839 (Box 16)
  - [Foster]Abby Kelley, 1844-1849 (Box 16)
  - [Foster]Abby Kelley 1830-1840-1843 (Box 17)
  - Foster, Abby Kelley 1837-1839-1845 (Box 17)
  - Fry, Elizabeth (Box 17)
  - Gage, Matilda Joslyn (Box 17)
  - Garrison, Helen (Box 17)
  - Garrison, William Lloyd (Box 17)
  - Garrison, William Lloyd, (Copies from the Alma Lutz Collection) (Box 17)
  - Gaskell, Mrs. (Box 17)
  - Godwin, Mary W. (Box 17)
  - Greeley, Horace (Box 17)
  - Grew, Mary, (Copies from the Alma Lutz Collection) (Box 17)
  - Grew, Mary (Box 17)
  - Griffing, Josephine S. (Box 17)
  - Grimke, Angelina E. (Box 17)
  - Grimke, Sarah, (Copies from the Alma Lutz Collection) (Box 17)
  - Grimke, Sarah and Angelina (Box 17)
  - Grimke Sisters,1805-1840 (Box 17)
  - Grimkes, 1839- (Box 17)
  - Guiney, Louise (Box 17)
  - Hale, Sarah J., (Copies from the Alma Lutz Collection) (Box 17)
  - Hale, Sarah J. — 1788-1879 (Box 17)
  - Harper, Ida Husted (Box 17)
  - Harper, Ida Husted — Letters, (Copies from the S.B.A Memorial Collection, 17 Madison St., Rochester, NY) (Box 17)
  - Hawley, Genevieve Lel, (Copies from the S.B.A Memorial Collection, 17 Madison St., Rochester, NY) (Box 17)
  - Hericourt, Jenny (Box 17)
  - Herttell, Judge — Married Women's Property Act (Box 17)
  - Higginson, Thomas Wentworth (Box 17)
  - Higginson, Thomas Wentworth (Box 17)
  - Holden, Miriam Y. (Box 17)
  - Hooker, Isabella Beecher (Box 17)
  - Hosmer, Harriet (Box 17)
  - Howe, Julia Ward and Daughter, (Copies from the Alma Lutz Collection) (Box 17)
  - Hutchinson, Abby (Box 17)
  - Isabella, Queen (Box 17)
  - Johnson, Oliver (Box 17)
  - Journalists — Women (Box 17)
  - Joy, Sally — Women Journalists (Box 17)
  - Keller, Helen (Box 17)
  - Kemble, Fanny (Box 17)
  - Kirchwey, Freda (Box 17)
  - Knight, Sarah Kemble (Box 17)
  - Larcom, Lucy and Lowell Mill Periodical (Box 17)
  - Lincoln, Mary (Box 17)
  - Lippencott, Sarah J. (Grace Greenwood) (Box 17)
  - Livermore, Mary A., (Copies - Originals Given to Radcliffe Women's Archives, 5/4/56) (Box 17)
  - Livermore, Mary, include. 2 photos taken from VC ind. stdts photofile (Box 17)
  - Lockwood, Belva, (Copies from the Alma Lutz Collection) (Box 17)
  - Lukens, Rebecca (Box 17)
  - Lyon, Mary, (Copies from the Alma Lutz Collection) (Box 17)
  - Lyon, Mary (Box 17)
  - Macaulay, Catharine (Box 17)
  - Martineau, Harriet, (Copies) (Box 17)
  - May, Samuel J. (Box 17)
  - McCord, Louisa C. (Box 17)
  - Merriam, Eve (Box 17)
  - Mill, John Stuart (Box 17)
  - Miller, M. Emma Guffey (Box 17)
  - Mitchell, Maria (Box 17)
  - Mitchell, Maria (Box 17)
  - Moody, Lady Deborah (Box 17)
  - More, Hannah (Box 17)
  - Morris, Esther Hobart (Box 17)
  - Mott, Lucretia, (Copies from the Alma Lutz Collection) (Box 17)
  - Mott, Lucretia, (Copies) (Box 17)
  - Mott, Lucretia and Lydia Mott (Box 17)
  - Mott, Lucretia — Clippings (Box 17)
  - Mott, John, (Copies from the Alma Lutz Collection) (Box 17)
  - New England Women (Box 17)
  - Nichols, Mary Gove (Box 17)
  - Nightingale, Florence (Box 17)
  - Ossoli, Margaret Fuller (Box 17)
  - Owen, Robert Dale (Box 17)
  - Owen, Robert Dale (Box 17)
  - Pankhurst, Emmeline and Christabel (Box 17)
  - Park, Alice (Box 17)
  - Parton, Sara (Box 17)
  - Penn, Hannah (Box 17)
  - Pethick — Lawrence, Lady (Box 17)
  - Phelps, Almira Hart Lincoln (Box 17)
  - Phillips, Wendell (Box 17)
  - Phillipa, Wendell and Ann — Play or Novel (Box 17)
  - Pierce, Sarah (Box 17)
  - Pillsbury, Parker, (Copies from the Alma Lutz Collection) (Box 17)
  - Quotations (Box 17)
  - Rankin, Jeannette (Box 17)
  - Ricker, Marilla M. (Box 17)
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor (Box 17)
  - Rose, Ernestine (Box 17)
  - Rose, Ernestine L., (Copies from the Alma Lutz Collection) (Box 17)
  - Rotch, Mary (Box 17)
  - Rowson, Susanna (Box 17)
  - Royall, Anne, (Copies from the Alma Lutz Collection) (Box 17)
  - Royall, Anne (Box 17)
  - Sanger, Margaret (Box 18)
  - Sargent, Ellen Clark (Box 18)
  - Schwimmer, Rosika (Box 18)
  - Selden, Judge Henry R.. (Box 18)
  - Severance, Caroline (Box 18)
  - Sewall, May Wright (Box 18)
  - Shaw, Anna Howard (Box 18)